

Christian De Leon

DevOps Engineer

Orlando, Florida (Prefer Remote) 305-905-7701 ChristianDeLeon12693@gmail.com

ChristianDeLeon.me - LinkedIn - GitHub

DevOps Engineer with 4+ years of experience in designing, deploying, and optimizing applications, microservices and cloud infrastructures. Highly motivated and always working above the baseline of expectation by continuously pushing myself to learn new and complex systems and technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

NDA - Independent Contract

June 2018 – July 2022 Remote

- Worked with a private investor as a solo engineer to research and develop applications to analyze and make investing recommendations.
- Developed event-driven microservices using IaC as Terraform,
 AWS CDK, CloudFormation which build and deploy resources
 such as Lambda, Step Functions, EventBridge, API Gateway, and
 SQS to process and analyze up to 10,000 messages a second.
- Used Kubernetes, AWS EC2, and ECS with Fargate run one billion simulations where the results were extracted, transformed, and saved using Redis, AWS DynamoDB, and RDS MySQL.
- Used Jenkins, Ansible, and AWS CodePipeline with CodeCommit, CodeBuild, and CodeDeploy as the CI/CD.
- Built user interfaces and charts to control and monitor services and analyze data using Prometheus, Grafana, Pandas, Matplotlib, and ReactJs.
- Developed Machine Learning Models and Deep Reinforcement Agents to assist in classifying, tracking, and predicting market trends.

Developer / Material Handler

Miami-Dade County Public Schools

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020 Miami, Florida

- Develop logistics applications using Visual Basic to aid in the weekly delivery of testing material for 500+ schools.
- Research and develop new methods of delivery, tracking, and organization.
- Track all inbound/outbound testing material.
- Prepare testing material for shipment to all MDCP Schools.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Amazon Web Services

CDK, CloudFormation, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, Lambda, EC2, ECS, ALB, ASG, API Gateway, Step Functions, RDS, DynamoDB

- Terraform
- Ubuntu
- Kubernetes
- Python
- Jenkins
- Bash
- Prometheus
- Git
- Docker
- SQL
- Ansible
- Redis
- RHEL

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified:
- o DevOps Engineer Professional
- o Solutions Architect Associate
- o SysOps Administrator Associate
- Developer Associate
- HashiCorp: Terraform Associate
- Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

In-Progress

- (Sept) Jenkins Engineer
- (Sept) Prometheus Associate
- (Sept) Red Hat Certified Engineer
- (Oct) Azure DevOps Engineer
- (Nov) GCP DevOps Engineer

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021

Southern New Hampshire University

Completed 63 hours towards B.S. in Computer Science

2016 - 2019

Florida International University

Completed 78 hours towards B.S. in Mechanical Engineering

2011 - 2016

Miami Dade College

A.A. in Mechanical Engineering

2007 - 2011

Christopher Columbus High School

High School Diploma